<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Larry Flint</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Larry Flint</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 16:20:41 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Antisyphon's SOC Core Skills</title><link>/posts/2022/w7d1-soc-core-skills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 16:20:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w7d1-soc-core-skills/</guid><description>Well today was a little weird for me as will all of this week, I normally wake up with codesignal, but the class I am taking starts at that time, so codesignal ended my day instead of started it. I did not get it quite done, but I did get the string separated and reversed correctly.
As for course work, I decided to disregard my sylabus, and instead take Antispyhon&amp;rsquo;s SOC Core Skills with John Strand.</description></item><item><title>N10-008 Training Course strikes back</title><link>/posts/2022/w6d5-networking-finale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 13:27:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w6d5-networking-finale/</guid><description>I made some progress in Codesignal today but, honestly still failing to loop backward correctly, it&amp;rsquo;s a hard thing to wrap my head around as python doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it naturally. I plan on spending more time on it tonight to see if I can get it as now that I have a mostly valid strategy I feel im close.
As far as course work I finished the N10-008 Training Course, and honestly I could not be happier to be done with this week.</description></item><item><title>N10-008 Training Course pt4</title><link>/posts/2022/w6d4-networking-pt4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 13:38:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w6d4-networking-pt4/</guid><description>Code signal today was more studying and looking at reverseInParentheses , and honestly I just can&amp;rsquo;t figure it out and I&amp;rsquo;m sick of looking at it trying to solve it. So, I asked a friend for help and he gave me how he did it in English, and I think I can bust that out tomorrow as it seems fairly easy, as frustrating as that is.
As for course work, I continued on with my good friend Professor Messor in the N10-008 Training Course.</description></item><item><title>N10-008 Training Course pt 3</title><link>/posts/2022/w6d3-networking-pt3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 15:41:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w6d3-networking-pt3/</guid><description>Welp, today for code signal, I did not write much code but instead study on what a stack is and how to use it, which is a last in first out data structure and you seem to make it with a list with .append(). I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a way to implement it though with this current problem but I feel like im getting close, although I thought this once before and ended up deleting all of that code.</description></item><item><title>N10-008 Training Course.. again</title><link>/posts/2022/w6d2-networking-pt2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 15:31:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w6d2-networking-pt2/</guid><description>Well, not gonna lie, I was so frustrated by CodeSignal yesterday that I skipped it today in favor of spending more time trying to understand networking. I do have some ideas on how to approach it after a talk with a friend, the finding the right parentheses problem is solved by first finding the first closing and going backward looking for the opening, but I&amp;rsquo;mm still fuzzy on how to go backward.</description></item><item><title>N10-008 Training Course</title><link>/posts/2022/w6d1-networking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 15:32:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w6d1-networking/</guid><description>Well, today started as most Mondays do, me staring at code signal trying to figure out reverseInParentheses with no progress. As is starting to become a pattern, after I was done working for the day, I came up with an idea to correctly add the third portion of the string after the middle has been reversed. While that worked kind of, it shined a light on several other factors that I had been dealing with wrong, like how I grabbed the parentheses and how I was overwriting my work every time I found new parentheses set.</description></item><item><title>A+ practice tests</title><link>/posts/2022/w5d5a+practicetests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 14:51:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w5d5a+practicetests/</guid><description>This morning&amp;rsquo;s code signal did not go that well. While I think my recursion idea would probably work, my method for grabbing the first closing parentheses won&amp;rsquo;t work, so I need to figure out a grab the last parentheses in a string. Also when I am splitting the string into thirds, I need to figure out the proper way to add the last third back more reliably. It is crashing right now, sometimes failing to find parentheses, and I am not entirely sure why my guard clause is not helping with that.</description></item><item><title>220-1102 Training Course pt 2</title><link>/posts/2022/w5d4-a+pt4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 16:27:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w5d4-a+pt4/</guid><description>Started off to a not-so-great day starting with making no progress on code signal today. The nested parentheses of the problem stump me. Although, as I am typing this I realized I might be able to use recursion to do it, after I identify the first parentheses, grab the whole substring and call the method again with the substring. That may work, I will have to try it tomorrow morning.</description></item><item><title>220-1102 Training Course</title><link>/posts/2022/w5d3a+pt3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 15:51:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w5d3a+pt3/</guid><description>well, I started still pretty stumped on reverseInParentheses, and made no progress on it this morning. Towards the end of the day I had an idea about using .index() to grab the second parentheses, so I typed all of that out and was working on trying to fine-tune it, and carefully reread the instructions and realized how they wanted me to handle the nested parentheses was not how I was doing it and the way I was doing it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description></item><item><title>220-1101 Training Course part 2</title><link>/posts/2022/w5d2-a+part2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 16:27:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w5d2-a+part2/</guid><description>Well, today started a little later than I wanted to because it was my daughter&amp;rsquo;s first day of kindergarten, and the line to drop her off was three blocks long. I made some slight progress on the code signal, I remembered that i could split the string by parentheses but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to grab the closing one parentheses.
As for course work today, I continued on my journey with the 220-1101 Training Course.</description></item><item><title>220-1101 Training Course</title><link>/posts/2022/w5d1-a+part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 15:49:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w5d1-a+part1/</guid><description>Monday mornings are my least favorite time of the week. CodeSignal was quite fruitful today, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a problem right, I feel like I almost have a good solution for reverseInParentheses. The basis of what I want to do is fairly simple. I need to go to every character in the input string and check if it is a parentheses, and once I find it I split the list into three pieces.</description></item><item><title>Mac indepedent study</title><link>/posts/2022/w4d5-macstudy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:13:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w4d5-macstudy/</guid><description>Still unsure of a good method of attack for Sort by Height . As I wrote that, I had an idea that did get me 2/5 test passed, but they are the ones that are just some edge case tests and I failed all of the actual tests. My idea seems solid to me though, so I am unsure of why it didn&amp;rsquo;t work.
For coursework today, there was none! It was an independent day, so that means after spending a little longer than normal starting at code signal I got to watch podcasts all day.</description></item><item><title>Apple Deployment and Management</title><link>/posts/2022/w4d4-mdmstudy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:29:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w4d4-mdmstudy/</guid><description>My brain felt like it was trying to come out of my skull all day today. I assumed it was because my body was experiencing what it was like to be without caffeine for the first time in fifteen years, but evolved into a full-grown migraine by the time my coffee was brewed and in my cup. So, my very foggy morning started with Sort by Height . Which, honestly, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get a concrete enough answer that was worth submitting today.</description></item><item><title>Learn How to Deploy and Manage Apple Devices</title><link>/posts/2022/w4d3-mdm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 14:21:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w4d3-mdm/</guid><description>Started this morning by solving commonCharacterCount after being one test short of it last night, then quickly solved isLucky. For course work, we are still in Macland, but today I went over Learn How to Deploy and Manage Apple Devices. Which is a bunch of really well-written articles on how to deploy Apple devices for your company. It seems like yesterday was a little bit of foreshadowing, and the main focus today was MDMs and how to use them.</description></item><item><title>Macos hijinks</title><link>/posts/2022/w4d2-mac_hijinks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 13:07:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w4d2-mac_hijinks/</guid><description>For CodeSignal today I spent my hour getting 9/10 test cases right on commonCharacterCount, but I am failing on a hidden test case. My coursework was not a normal day. I started with the MacBook, which after being left on and plugged in overnight had still not booted to the login screen. After a hard reset, I noticed it progressed to about the exact spot and froze. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what was going on, so I went through the time-consuming process of repeating my steps yesterday thinking maybe something failed and I did not notice.</description></item><item><title>Learn How To Support Apple Devices - Mac</title><link>/posts/2022/w4d1-macsupport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 08:05:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w4d1-macsupport/</guid><description>Well, I cheated over the weekend and got help on almostincreasing. I still need to study the answer because I do not understand it, but this morning I tried to redeem myself by solving matrixElementsSum and All Longest Strings almost immediately. Although, matrixEWlementSum took me a little longer to get it&amp;rsquo;s more edge cases.
This week for course work it&amp;rsquo;s all about mac baby, I have acquired an older intel silicon mac to work on, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to learn how to factory reset on my machine.</description></item><item><title>Google Meet, Google Chat and Google Sheets - Advanced Topics</title><link>/posts/2022/w3d4-googlesuite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 17:29:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w3d4-googlesuite/</guid><description>Today we continued on our google suite adventures by taking two courses, Google Meet and Google Chat and Google Sheets - Advanced Topics. They both followed what I had dubbed the google suite format. Videos with small exercises, a quiz periodically, and at the end a small capstone project.
The google meet and chat course was fairly similar to the other social google apps, and talked about how to set up and join meetings and the basics of google chat.</description></item><item><title>Google Sheets and Google Slides</title><link>/posts/2022/w3d3-googlesuite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 17:37:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w3d3-googlesuite/</guid><description>Struggled for another hour on almostincreamenting, tried some things that didn&amp;rsquo;t work, and starting to feel fairly frustrated with it, but I am sure it&amp;rsquo;s a little detail I will feel dumb about missing once I get it. For the coursework today I did two more applications in the google suite, Google Slides and Google Sheets. They follow the same format as the previous courses I have done this week.</description></item><item><title>Google docs and Google drive</title><link>/posts/2022/w3d2-googlesuite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:19:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w3d2-googlesuite/</guid><description>So today is kinda a twofer as there was no blog yesterday due to a nasty finger cut. The courses I took were Gmail, Google Calendar, Google Docs and Google Drive. The course itself was formatted with a few videos followed by exercises following what the videos talked about. It was broken up into sections by quizzes, then to top it off at the end there is a final challenge that goes over everything you have learned about.</description></item><item><title>Confluence Fundamentals and Trello Fundamentals</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d5-trello+confluence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 13:37:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d5-trello+confluence/</guid><description>Yay a Saturday blog post, my work week is weird this week with me being sick on Thursday. Today&amp;rsquo;s coursework was more Atlassian products starting with Confluence Fundamentals, which is an application that I&amp;rsquo;m assuming companies are using when they say have a company wiki. It followed the same pattern as yesterday&amp;rsquo;s courses, small paragraphs followed by diagrams to explain, topped off with a quiz at the end to make sure you comprehend it.</description></item><item><title>Jira Fundamentals and Jira Service Management Fundamentals</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d3-jira/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 18:18:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d3-jira/</guid><description>Today I overslept a bit because I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel well yesterday, so I decided to skip Codesignal and moved right into coursework. I have moved beyond Okta for now and am diving into the world of Jira, which starts off by me taking Jira Fundamentals and Jira Service Management Fundamentals. The course is short paragraphs followed by a GIF to show you what they are explaining, with little quizzes at the end of each chapter to make sure you are staying caught up.</description></item><item><title>Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity day 2</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d2-okta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 16:14:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d2-okta/</guid><description>I made some progress on almostIncreasingSequence by getting rid of everything I had, and rewriting it using zip to pair off the list and comparing the pairs. For my coursework, I continue on Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity. It was not designed for someone without the hardware to run okta on. The course is mostly just articles to read, with some short videos in between. There are some more involved things to do if you do happen to have a windows server lying around, but I read through them instead.</description></item><item><title>Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity day one</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d1-okta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 17:41:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d1-okta/</guid><description>Today started strong with me finally getting over some blockers and making progress in almostIncreasingSequence, only to find new ones. My method right now permanently deletes x + 1 in the list, but sometimes X needs to be deleted and I need to figure out a way to decipher that. As far as course work goes I started Otka training today, or attempted to. My 8-week IT crash course has me taking the next few days Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity.</description></item><item><title>Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment</title><link>/posts/2022/itday5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 14:55:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday5/</guid><description>Today I spent my code signal time failing again to solve almostIncreasingSequence. After talking to a friend about it, I think I may have a solution that I plan to test out over the weekend. It was the last day of the Google workspace course and it ended with Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment. This course was based on a company of about 250 people who were switching over from a legacy provider.</description></item><item><title>Google Workspace Mail Management</title><link>/posts/2022/itday4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 17:11:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday4/</guid><description>Today during Codesignal time I did not manage to solve any, but worked on almostIncreasingSequence for the whole hour, unable to find a complete solution. For course work today it was Google Workspace Mail Management which started with a warning to not change your DNS records if you are not using a test site. It started off by explaining how to set up MX records for google workspace, which I had to do already in the first course as I was not using a domain set up by Google.</description></item><item><title>Google Workspace Security</title><link>/posts/2022/itday3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:45:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday3/</guid><description>Started off the day with code signal, as usual, solved Make Array Consecutive 2 pretty easily, although I did have to spend a few minutes looking for a solution without recursion. Today&amp;rsquo;s course was Google Workspace Security. It went over the security features of Google workspace and how to use them. There was a lot more reading than usual for the courses. Although I did do things like setting up and enforcing 2fa on a company-wide level, and changing session controls so that users will log out more often and single sign-on.</description></item><item><title>Managing Google Workspace</title><link>/posts/2022/idday2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:07:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/idday2/</guid><description>Today I started late due to a doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment in the morning that ended up taking about half of the time that I would prefer to be working so I skipped codesignal today and jumped to my next course as soon as I got home. Today I took Managing Google Workspace. It followed the same format as the last one: an intro video to introduce the section, a couple of guided assignments followed by a quiz to ensure you understood it.</description></item><item><title>IT Day One</title><link>/posts/2022/itday1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 13:54:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday1/</guid><description>Well, after being put off by almost a week due to a freak power outage, today was day one of my eight-week IT crash course put together by my friend. It started off a little rocky as the Introduction to Google Workspace Administration I followed today, assuming I was starting fresh and buying a domain and letting google set up their DNS records. Since I already had a domain, and no spare money, I decided not to do this and go through with using my own domain for this course.</description></item><item><title>Alien invasion</title><link>/posts/2022/alien_invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:35:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/alien_invasion/</guid><description>Ever since I was little I have been fascinated by video games and everything about them. As I have been learning to code, naturally I have been very interested in how video games are made but with no experience building video games and less than a year of experience writing code, it seemed like a tall order. But I was still curious and ended up following a tutorial to build a Space Invaders inspired game from a tutorial I found in Python crash course by Eric Matthes.</description></item><item><title>Meet Addy</title><link>/posts/2022/addy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/addy/</guid><description>I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
During my exploration with Addy there have been many hurdles and many lessons learned.</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>/welcome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:30:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>/welcome/</guid><description>Hey! Welcome to my site. This is where I post finished projects and blog entries detailing my work process. If you have any questions feel free to get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 10:16:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description> Name* Email* Subject* Message Send</description></item><item><title>Budget App</title><link>/posts/2022/budget-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:32:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/budget-app/</guid><description>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.
Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.</description></item><item><title>Project: Forum API</title><link>/posts/2022/forum-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/forum-api/</guid><description>This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.
This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description>Addy I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
During my exploration with Addy there have been many hurdles and many lessons learned.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:24:46 -0800</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>One of my earliest memories in the world of programming was my grandfather teaching me how to change the screensaver in Windows 95 when I was about 4 years old. Not the most technically challenging project by any means, but from that point on I was hooked. I simply had to know how these things worked.
From that first simple lesson, family has played a huge role in my progression as a programmer.</description></item><item><title/><link>/thankyou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thankyou/</guid><description>Thanks for reaching out! I’ll get back to you as soon as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>