<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Larry Flint</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Larry Flint</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 17:37:37 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Sheets and Google Slides</title><link>/posts/2022/w3d3-googlesuite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 17:37:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w3d3-googlesuite/</guid><description>Struggled for another hour on almostincreamenting, tried some things that didn&amp;rsquo;t work, and starting to feel fairly frustrated with it, but I am sure it&amp;rsquo;s a little detail I will feel dumb about missing once I get it. For the coursework today I did two more applications in the google suite, Google Slides and Google Sheets. They follow the same format as the previous courses I have done this week.</description></item><item><title>Google docs and Google drive</title><link>/posts/2022/w3d2-googlesuite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:19:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w3d2-googlesuite/</guid><description>So today is kinda a twofer as there was no blog yesterday due to a nasty finger cut. The courses I took were Gmail, Google Calendar, Google Docs and Google Drive. The course itself was formatted with a few videos followed by exercises following what the videos talked about. It was broken up into sections by quizzes, then to top it off at the end there is a final challenge that goes over everything you have learned about.</description></item><item><title>Confluence Fundamentals and Trello Fundamentals</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d5-trello+confluence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 13:37:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d5-trello+confluence/</guid><description>Yay a Saturday blog post, my work week is weird this week with me being sick on Thursday. Today&amp;rsquo;s coursework was more Atlassian products starting with Confluence Fundamentals, which is an application that I&amp;rsquo;m assuming companies are using when they say have a company wiki. It followed the same pattern as yesterday&amp;rsquo;s courses, small paragraphs followed by diagrams to explain, topped off with a quiz at the end to make sure you comprehend it.</description></item><item><title>Jira Fundamentals and Jira Service Management Fundamentals</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d3-jira/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 18:18:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d3-jira/</guid><description>Today I overslept a bit because I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel well yesterday, so I decided to skip Codesignal and moved right into coursework. I have moved beyond Okta for now and am diving into the world of Jira, which starts off by me taking Jira Fundamentals and Jira Service Management Fundamentals. The course is short paragraphs followed by a GIF to show you what they are explaining, with little quizzes at the end of each chapter to make sure you are staying caught up.</description></item><item><title>Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity day 2</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d2-okta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 16:14:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d2-okta/</guid><description>I made some progress on almostIncreasingSequence by getting rid of everything I had, and rewriting it using zip to pair off the list and comparing the pairs. For my coursework, I continue on Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity. It was not designed for someone without the hardware to run okta on. The course is mostly just articles to read, with some short videos in between. There are some more involved things to do if you do happen to have a windows server lying around, but I read through them instead.</description></item><item><title>Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity day one</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d1-okta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 17:41:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d1-okta/</guid><description>Today started strong with me finally getting over some blockers and making progress in almostIncreasingSequence, only to find new ones. My method right now permanently deletes x + 1 in the list, but sometimes X needs to be deleted and I need to figure out a way to decipher that. As far as course work goes I started Otka training today, or attempted to. My 8-week IT crash course has me taking the next few days Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity.</description></item><item><title>Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment</title><link>/posts/2022/itday5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 14:55:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday5/</guid><description>Today I spent my code signal time failing again to solve almostIncreasingSequence. After talking to a friend about it, I think I may have a solution that I plan to test out over the weekend. It was the last day of the Google workspace course and it ended with Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment. This course was based on a company of about 250 people who were switching over from a legacy provider.</description></item><item><title>Google Workspace Mail Management</title><link>/posts/2022/itday4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 17:11:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday4/</guid><description>Today during Codesignal time I did not manage to solve any, but worked on almostIncreasingSequence for the whole hour, unable to find a complete solution. For course work today it was Google Workspace Mail Management which started with a warning to not change your DNS records if you are not using a test site. It started off by explaining how to set up MX records for google workspace, which I had to do already in the first course as I was not using a domain set up by Google.</description></item><item><title>Google Workspace Security</title><link>/posts/2022/itday3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:45:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday3/</guid><description>Started off the day with code signal, as usual, solved Make Array Consecutive 2 pretty easily, although I did have to spend a few minutes looking for a solution without recursion. Today&amp;rsquo;s course was Google Workspace Security. It went over the security features of Google workspace and how to use them. There was a lot more reading than usual for the courses. Although I did do things like setting up and enforcing 2fa on a company-wide level, and changing session controls so that users will log out more often and single sign-on.</description></item><item><title>Managing Google Workspace</title><link>/posts/2022/idday2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:07:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/idday2/</guid><description>Today I started late due to a doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment in the morning that ended up taking about half of the time that I would prefer to be working so I skipped codesignal today and jumped to my next course as soon as I got home. Today I took Managing Google Workspace. It followed the same format as the last one: an intro video to introduce the section, a couple of guided assignments followed by a quiz to ensure you understood it.</description></item><item><title>IT Day One</title><link>/posts/2022/itday1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 13:54:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday1/</guid><description>Well, after being put off by almost a week due to a freak power outage, today was day one of my eight-week IT crash course put together by my friend. It started off a little rocky as the Introduction to Google Workspace Administration I followed today, assuming I was starting fresh and buying a domain and letting google set up their DNS records. Since I already had a domain, and no spare money, I decided not to do this and go through with using my own domain for this course.</description></item><item><title>Alien invasion</title><link>/posts/2022/alien_invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:35:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/alien_invasion/</guid><description>Ever since I was little I have been fascinated by video games and everything about them. As I have been learning to code, naturally I have been very interested in how video games are made but with no experience building video games and less than a year of experience writing code, it seemed like a tall order. But I was still curious and ended up following a tutorial to build a Space Invaders inspired game from a tutorial I found in Python crash course by Eric Matthes.</description></item><item><title>Meet Addy</title><link>/posts/2022/addy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/addy/</guid><description>I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
During my exploration with Addy there have been many hurdles and many lessons learned.</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>/welcome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:30:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>/welcome/</guid><description>Hey! Welcome to my site. This is where I post finished projects and blog entries detailing my work process. If you have any questions feel free to get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 10:16:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description> Name* Email* Subject* Message Send</description></item><item><title>Budget App</title><link>/posts/2022/budget-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:32:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/budget-app/</guid><description>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.
Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.</description></item><item><title>Project: Forum API</title><link>/posts/2022/forum-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/forum-api/</guid><description>This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.
This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description>Addy I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
During my exploration with Addy there have been many hurdles and many lessons learned.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:24:46 -0800</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>One of my earliest memories in the world of programming was my grandfather teaching me how to change the screensaver in Windows 95 when I was about 4 years old. Not the most technically challenging project by any means, but from that point on I was hooked. I simply had to know how these things worked.
From that first simple lesson, family has played a huge role in my progression as a programmer.</description></item><item><title/><link>/thankyou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thankyou/</guid><description>Thanks for reaching out! I’ll get back to you as soon as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>