<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Larry Flint</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Larry Flint</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Index</title><link>/posts/2022/addy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/addy/</guid><description>Meet Addy I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions, other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
Addy doesn’t have a central theme as she really was meant to be a personal project, thus each of her commands came about simply from asking myself “Wouldn’t it be cool if…?</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>/welcome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:30:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>/welcome/</guid><description>Hey! Welcome to my site. This is where I post finished projects and blog entries detailing my work process. If you have any questions feel free to get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 10:16:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description> var submitted=false; Name* Email* Subject* Message Send</description></item><item><title>Budget App</title><link>/posts/2022/budget-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:32:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/budget-app/</guid><description>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.
Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.</description></item><item><title>Project: Forum API</title><link>/posts/2022/forum-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/forum-api/</guid><description>This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.
This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description>Forum api This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.
This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:24:46 -0800</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>One of my earliest memories in the world of programming was my grandfather teaching me how to change the screensaver in Windows 95 when I was about 4 years old. Not the most technically challenging project by any means, but from that point on I was hooked. I simply had to know how these things worked.
From that first simple lesson, family has played a huge role in my progression as a programmer.</description></item><item><title/><link>/thankyou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thankyou/</guid><description>Thanks for reaching out! I’ll get back to you as soon as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>