<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Larry Flint</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Larry Flint</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Index</title><link>/posts/2022/addy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/addy/</guid><description>Meet Addy I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions, other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
Addy doesn’t have a central theme as she really was meant to be a personal project, thus each of her commands came about simply from asking myself “Wouldn’t it be cool if…?</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="meet-addy">Meet Addy</h1>
<p><img src="/project-pictures/addy-help.png" alt="addy-help"></p>
<p>I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions, other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.</p>
<p>Addy doesn’t have a central theme as she really was meant to be a personal project, thus each of her commands came about simply from asking myself “Wouldn’t it be cool if…?”</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>A backend to complement her, and allow to me save data more reliably.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A way for her to play music in a voice channel (worried about the legality here).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A Runescape item price look-up. (Their api is really bad, the easiest way to do this is to build a webcrawler and crawl their api once a week)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you have a cool idea for Addy, contact me and let me know!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are interested in seeing Addy in action, I have set up a <a href="https://discord.gg/a5EXHbGwzH">discord server</a> for you to try. The browser version of discord doesn&rsquo;t require you to log in.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Acer0ni/Addy-the-disc-bot">Github repo</a>for you to try, the browser version of discord doesn’t require you to log in.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Budget App</title><link>/posts/2022/budget-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:32:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/budget-app/</guid><description>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.
Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/project-pictures/bb-pic.png" alt="BB-pic"></p>
<p>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.</p>
<p>Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.e vacations.</p>
<p>I worked mostly on the back end for this project but did help on some of the front end logic with the api calls. the back end turned out pretty much how I expected it to after several iteration.</p>
<p>It seemed like everything was going alright early on, we had spent a bunch of time planning the front end thinking the back end would be self explanatory&hellip; it was not.  We ran into issues immediately with the back end not returning things the front end devs thought they would, we fixed this by working very closely the rest of the week and over communicating.</p>
<p>This project really taught me the importance of having a solid design in both your front and back end and really to be clear in your api documentation.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Team-formerly-known-as/budget-book-backend">Github repo backend</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Team-formerly-known-as/budget-book-frontend">Github repo Frontend</a></p>
<p><a href="https://team-formerly-known-as.github.io/budget-book-frontend/">live site</a></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Project: Forum API</title><link>/posts/2022/forum-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/forum-api/</guid><description>This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.
This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/project-pictures/db-picture.png" alt="db-icon">This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.</p>
<p>This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources. We had five days to complete this project.</p>
<p>Not knowing anything about Django-Ninja coming in, or anything about cookie based authentication, I spent more time studying than coding, and did not finish the front end. However, I did end up with a fully functional secure api with cookie based authentication.</p>
<p>One immediate challenge was the lack of Django-Ninja docs written on a beginner level. So there was a lot of struggle trying to fit django-ninja into what i already knew about DRF.</p>
<p>I had a lot of fun with Django-Ninjas auto-docs. They made testing very easy. My most valuable lesson from this project came in the form of setting realistic expectations when incorporating a new technology into a build. Django-Ninja did make the process much quicker once I had done enough research to fully understand it, however I underestimated the amount of time it took to get to that point which caused a delay in finishing the project.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Acer0ni/coding-forum">Github repo</a></p>
<p><a href="https://forum.pwnschool.org/api/docs">Live site</a></p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>