<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Larry Flint</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Larry Flint</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 17:41:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity day one</title><link>/posts/2022/w2d1-okta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 17:41:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/w2d1-okta/</guid><description>Today started strong with me finally getting over some blockers and making progress in almostIncreasingSequence, only to find new ones. My method right now permanently deletes x + 1 in the list, but sometimes X needs to be deleted and I need to figure out a way to decipher that. As far as course work goes I started Otka training today, or attempted to. My 8-week IT crash course has me taking the next few days Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today started strong with me finally getting over some blockers and making progress in <a href="https://app.codesignal.com/arcade/intro/level-2/2mxbGwLzvkTCKAJMG">almostIncreasingSequence</a>, only to find new ones. My method right now permanently deletes <code>x + 1</code> in the list, but sometimes X needs to be deleted and I need to figure out a way to decipher that. As far as course work goes I started Otka training today, or attempted to. My 8-week IT crash course has me taking the next few days <a href="https://www.okta.com/training/okta-basics-curriculum-for-workforce-identity">Okta Basics Curriculum for Workforce Identity</a>. I was held back originally by the site having latency issues which cut into a significant portion of my work day. Once the site was back up I started going to the lessons. They were not as nice as the Google workspace lessons, but they will do fine. The ones I took today covered some terms that they will be using and how to add users to add to Okta, as well as what Okta is, an identity as a service platform that helps corporate users manage their single login.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment</title><link>/posts/2022/itday5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 14:55:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday5/</guid><description>Today I spent my code signal time failing again to solve almostIncreasingSequence. After talking to a friend about it, I think I may have a solution that I plan to test out over the weekend. It was the last day of the Google workspace course and it ended with Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment. This course was based on a company of about 250 people who were switching over from a legacy provider.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I spent my code signal time failing again to solve <a href="https://app.codesignal.com/arcade/intro/level-2/2mxbGwLzvkTCKAJMG">almostIncreasingSequence</a>. After talking to a friend about it, I think I may have a solution that I plan to test out over the weekend. It was the last day of the Google workspace course and it ended with <a href="https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/course_templates/93">Planning for a Google Workspace Deployment</a>. This course was based on a company of about 250 people who were switching over from a legacy provider. In practice, it was kind of like a review and I didn&rsquo;t learn anything new with it, and a lot of what they were saying was hard to follow without some experience in IT or having ever even been in a company with 250 people in it. It was kind of like the rest of the courses had been giving me puzzle pieces and this one was putting the puzzle together. In truth this is probably the only course I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend to someone starting off learning it, without some real-world experience it had little to offer.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Google Workspace Mail Management</title><link>/posts/2022/itday4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 17:11:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday4/</guid><description>Today during Codesignal time I did not manage to solve any, but worked on almostIncreasingSequence for the whole hour, unable to find a complete solution. For course work today it was Google Workspace Mail Management which started with a warning to not change your DNS records if you are not using a test site. It started off by explaining how to set up MX records for google workspace, which I had to do already in the first course as I was not using a domain set up by Google.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today during Codesignal time I did not manage to solve any, but worked on <a href="https://app.codesignal.com/arcade/intro/level-2/2mxbGwLzvkTCKAJMG">almostIncreasingSequence</a> for the whole hour, unable to find a complete solution. For course work today it was <a href="https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/course_templates/91">Google Workspace Mail Management</a> which started with a warning to not change your DNS records if you are not using a test site. It started off by explaining how to set up MX records for google workspace, which I had to do already in the first course as I was not using a domain set up by Google. After that, we went into how to secure your domain&rsquo;s email, including setting up SPF records and dmarc and DKIM. It ended the course doing more google admin dashboard stuff, like setting up a block and allow list for incoming and outgoing emails, and how to set up a compliance filter to make sure that none of the employees are saying any naughty words. It&rsquo;s a very useful course in how to set all this up in google workspace.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Google Workspace Security</title><link>/posts/2022/itday3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:45:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday3/</guid><description>Started off the day with code signal, as usual, solved Make Array Consecutive 2 pretty easily, although I did have to spend a few minutes looking for a solution without recursion. Today&amp;rsquo;s course was Google Workspace Security. It went over the security features of Google workspace and how to use them. There was a lot more reading than usual for the courses. Although I did do things like setting up and enforcing 2fa on a company-wide level, and changing session controls so that users will log out more often and single sign-on.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Started off the day with code signal, as usual, solved <a href="https://app.codesignal.com/arcade/intro/level-2/bq2XnSr5kbHqpHGJC">Make Array Consecutive 2</a> pretty easily, although I did have to spend a few minutes looking for a solution without recursion. Today&rsquo;s course was <a href="https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/course_templates/48">Google Workspace Security</a>. It went over the security features of Google workspace and how to use them. There was a lot more reading than usual for the courses. Although I did do things like setting up and enforcing 2fa on a company-wide level, and changing session controls so that users will log out more often and single sign-on. This is where the struggles started for me, a combination of not reading the directions carefully and poorly worded directions didn&rsquo;t make it clear that I was supposed to make a <a href="https://www.15five.com/">15five account</a> before setting anything up. Once I caught that mistake and had it set up correctly it still did not work. I tested it on another account and realized that the SSO was failing because it was trying to sign up using OAuth instead of sso. Once I took 15five&rsquo;s OAuth permission away it all worked perfectly. After that, it was log viewing time which once again was pretty boring because of no activity.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Managing Google Workspace</title><link>/posts/2022/idday2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:07:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/idday2/</guid><description>Today I started late due to a doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment in the morning that ended up taking about half of the time that I would prefer to be working so I skipped codesignal today and jumped to my next course as soon as I got home. Today I took Managing Google Workspace. It followed the same format as the last one: an intro video to introduce the section, a couple of guided assignments followed by a quiz to ensure you understood it.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I started late due to a doctor&rsquo;s appointment in the morning that ended up taking about half of the time that I would prefer to be working so I skipped codesignal today and jumped to my next course as soon as I got home. Today I took <a href="https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/course_templates/92">Managing Google Workspace</a>. It followed the same format as the last one: an intro video to introduce the section, a couple of guided assignments followed by a quiz to ensure you understood it. Today was a bit of a struggle because the course is slightly outdated and google has moved or renamed elements but Google Workspace is set up very logically. Once I realized that I was following the wrong instructions it was not usually hard to explore around and find where they moved the setting I was looking for.</p>
<p>It took me through managing some of the more popular Google apps from a business side things like, calendar,gmail, and vault. I did things like set a data retention plan in google vault, close off access to certain apps at a company level and a group level, transfer ownership of files from a deleted account to an active one, and view the audit logs. today was undoubtedly less interesting today than it was yesterday, some things I only read through and couldn&rsquo;t do like adding a second domain or creating a mobile account, and the log section was practically empty due to the fact that I don&rsquo;t have a company. all and all a good course and I am excited to see what tomorrow brings me.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>IT Day One</title><link>/posts/2022/itday1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 13:54:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/itday1/</guid><description>Well, after being put off by almost a week due to a freak power outage, today was day one of my eight-week IT crash course put together by my friend. It started off a little rocky as the Introduction to Google Workspace Administration I followed today, assuming I was starting fresh and buying a domain and letting google set up their DNS records. Since I already had a domain, and no spare money, I decided not to do this and go through with using my own domain for this course.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, after being put off by almost a week due to a freak power outage, today was day one of my eight-week IT crash course put together by my <a href="https://0xda.de/">friend</a>. It started off a little rocky as the <a href="https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/course_templates/90">Introduction to Google Workspace Administration</a> I followed today, assuming I was starting fresh and buying a domain and letting google set up their DNS records. Since I already had a domain, and no spare money, I decided not to do this and go through with using my own domain for this course. It took me a while to realize I needed to set up my own MX records, and I should have already done so before I backtracked and followed googles instructions on adding the correct MX records, which of course failed their tests right away. After an embarrassingly long time, I read the instructions again and see that some registrars require a &ldquo;.&rdquo; at the end of the value. So I added my &ldquo;.&quot;&rsquo;s and went on with my course.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/E9IwVdb.png" alt="Imgur"></p>
<p>From here it was like a guided walkthrough of Google workspace. It took me through the features and had me do a little task in each. Things like adding users, making mailing groups, settings different users, and groups of users to have different permissions. All and all it was a fun course to go through and see some of the tools an IT manager has at their disposal and I look forward to what tomorrow brings me.</p>
<p>Codesignal was un-eventful today, I completed this <a href="https://app.codesignal.com/arcade/intro/level-2/yuGuHvcCaFCKk56rJ">Shape area</a>. I looked for a pattern to no avail for a solid 15 minutes. Before going to google to look up what the heck an interesting polygon was and was met with thousands of answers to this exact same problem. Not understanding most of them, and not being comfortable &ldquo;borrowing&rdquo; code that I don&rsquo;t understand, I spent a while finding an answer.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Alien invasion</title><link>/posts/2022/alien_invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:35:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/alien_invasion/</guid><description>Ever since I was little I have been fascinated by video games and everything about them. As I have been learning to code, naturally I have been very interested in how video games are made but with no experience building video games and less than a year of experience writing code, it seemed like a tall order. But I was still curious and ended up following a tutorial to build a Space Invaders inspired game from a tutorial I found in Python crash course by Eric Matthes.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/7L395bz.png" alt="Imgur"></p>
<p>Ever since I was little I have been fascinated by video games and everything about them. As I have been learning to code, naturally I have been very interested in how video games are made but with no experience building video games and less than a year of experience writing code, it seemed like a tall order. But I was still curious and ended up following a tutorial to build a Space Invaders inspired game from a tutorial I found in <a href="https://nostarch.com/pythoncrashcourse2e">Python crash course</a> by Eric Matthes.</p>
<p>The idea started to form as the tutorial walked me through setting up high scores for the game. Still, a problem that bugged me immediately was that there was no persistence there so as soon as I exited the app the high scores were gone forever and I would never be able to brag to my friends about my sweet new score. After the tutorial was finished I went back and refactored it to save the high scores locally but that still seemed hollow to me in today&rsquo;s connected world. After a little research on how bigger games handle this problem, I learned that my plan wouldn&rsquo;t be perfect – anyone with an account could make an API call directly to the server and have an impossibly high score. Real online games handle this a lot of the time by keeping state server side to make sure there is nothing fishy going on. This would require a full refactor and be outside of the score for this project. With a notepad full of ideas and notes, I started writing a server that takes care of authentication and keeps track of the high scores. With plenty of ideas for the future, such as seasonal high scores, a personal top ten, and some sweet power-up for your ship in the game, I decided to focus on getting this first idea shipped.</p>
<p>I began designing the server component for it, that being the part that I had done before. I used Django to keep track of the users and cookie-based authentication which did the brunt of the work for me. I ended up only needing four routes to make this happen: signup, a login, a submit score, and a get score to make this game run but ended up adding a get users and get all scores for testing purposes and it seemed like they would be helpful to have in the future.</p>
<p>Once the server was done, it was time to hook the game up to it, and honestly, I was at a loss. I knew exactly as much of Pygame as the tutorial had taught me, which unfortunately for me was not the same knowledge I needed to do what I wanted to do. Improvements like adding multiple screens to the game, having error boxes pop up, and making requests to an API were all beyond the scope of the tutorial and just beyond my knowledge level. I spent a few days thinking about the overall design of the game and how I could slip a login screen into it without refactoring the whole thing. Once I felt I had a clear path I jumped in and started coding. I knew I needed to make a screen with text boxes for username and password and buttons to navigate through the different screens, a similar screen to register an account, and a few well-placed requests. At the end of the project, it ended up pretty much how I had planned in the beginning.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/bKzbbmR.png" alt="Imgur"></p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/o4OH62y.png" alt="Imgur"></p>
<h2 id="deployment">Deployment</h2>
<p>While the coding of the project went well the deployment was rocky, because the server was going to be hosted remotely I decided that dockerizing it would be the best path. Docker is a great tool that I have used once before and was happy to get some more experience with so that part was pretty straightforward. Pairing it with Nginx so that it could talk to the container took me a while and I needed a fair bit of help to get it done. The deployment process looks roughly like this.</p>
<ul>
<li>pull the project from the repo on the server</li>
<li>build the docker container</li>
<li>set up Postgres</li>
<li>run the docker container</li>
<li>set up Nginx</li>
<li>???</li>
<li>profit</li>
</ul>
<p>Editor’s Note: The challenges with Nginx were primarily deploying the application in a container but running Nginx on the host as a reverse proxy for multiple applications.</p>
<h2 id="distribution">Distribution</h2>
<p>I thought distributing the game would be easy. Until I started writing the readme for the repo and as I write my technical docs as if I was explaining them to my grandma I knew I was losing a lot of potential users if my install instructions included the command line. I looked around and found <a href="https://pyinstaller.org/en/stable/">Pyinstaller</a> and learned how to use that. After two days of making sure I have the right python version installed and studying which flags to use to get a single executable (including the fact that even if Pyinstaller said that my game was one file I still had to make sure to package my assets into the root directory) I finally had it. Executables for both Mac and windows, which I had to build on their respective machines. I moved the binary to my wife&rsquo;s computer and tried to run it… only to be met with a windows defender alert. So I ran it through <a href="https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/42bddc5b361faa09bc1b346dc8c83d752e3041cb4b3da3d1a9bb010bac4094d3?nocache=1">virus total</a> and found that 6 security vendors flagged it as malware. It turns out a package that pyinstaller uses was flagged as <a href="https://github.com/pyinstaller/pyinstaller/issues/6754">malware</a>. It seems this is a known problem and I am not the first person to encounter it. I decided that I had sunk enough time into this part of the project and decided to try to build binaries in a later version.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Looking back, this project gave me more experience building an API with authentication and gave me a reason to use Docker and Nginx again. I feel I need a lot more experience with the deployment side of development, so it was valuable to practice it here. But I think I would not do a project like this by myself again. I found myself spending too much time doing things that I didn&rsquo;t enjoy, like lining everything up, and not enough time doing what I did enjoy, building functional features.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Acer0ni/alien-invasion">Github Repo</a></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Meet Addy</title><link>/posts/2022/addy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:25:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/addy/</guid><description>I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.
During my exploration with Addy there have been many hurdles and many lessons learned.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/project-pictures/addy-help.png" alt="addy-help"></p>
<p>I started this project as a way to break out of the rut I found myself in during the planning phase for a much larger app. With no concrete intentions other than exploring a few different APIs and building something cool, I started writing, researching, experimenting, and now I’m extremely happy to present the result of this endeavour: Addy the Discord Bot.</p>
<p>During my exploration with Addy there have been many hurdles and many lessons learned.</p>
<p>Here are some of the things I have learned from the journey so far:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>How to handle third party APIs with less than stellar documentation and design</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How to save data without making a database</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The python requests library, and how to handle it&rsquo;s response object</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Explored Python&rsquo;s dictionary and it&rsquo;s functions</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Addy doesn’t have a central theme as she really was meant to be a personal project, thus each of her commands came about simply from asking myself “Wouldn’t it be cool if…?” Here are some of the things she can do now:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Look up a player in Runescape3</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Create and add to a watch2gether room for you and your friends</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Offer a word of encouragement or tell you a quote from Brooklyn 99</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course every new feature sparks ideas for other improvements and the list keeps growing, but here are the additions I would like to make in the near future:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>A backend to complement her, and allow to me save data more reliably.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A way for her to play music in a voice channel (worried about the legality here).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A Runescape item price look-up. (Their api is really bad, the easiest way to do this is to build a webcrawler and crawl their api once a week)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you have a cool idea for Addy, contact me and let me know!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are interested in seeing Addy in action, I have set up a <a href="https://discord.gg/a5EXHbGwzH">discord server</a> for you to try. The browser version of discord doesn&rsquo;t require you to log in. Jump right in and type !help to see all of her commands. a more in depth explanation can be found <a href="https://github.com/Acer0ni/Addy-the-disc-bot/blob/main/README.md">here.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Acer0ni/Addy-the-disc-bot">Github repo</a></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Budget App</title><link>/posts/2022/budget-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:32:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/budget-app/</guid><description>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.
Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/project-pictures/bb-pic.png" alt="BB-pic"></p>
<p>Budgetbook is a minimalist budget tracking app. The user starts by inputting their monthly income, then adds expenses with dollar values which are automatically subtracted from the monthly total. Expenses can be edited and deleted, with the user’s remaining monthly balance updating automatically to match.</p>
<p>Budget book was our first time working with other developers on a major project. We set off to make a full Stack budgeting application that took in your monthly income and expenses, and told you how much remaining and let you set goals to work for i.e vacations.</p>
<p>I worked mostly on the back end for this project but did help on some of the front end logic with the api calls. the back end turned out pretty much how I expected it to after several iteration.</p>
<p>It seemed like everything was going alright early on, we had spent a bunch of time planning the front end thinking the back end would be self explanatory&hellip; it was not.  We ran into issues immediately with the back end not returning things the front end devs thought they would, we fixed this by working very closely the rest of the week and over communicating.</p>
<p>This project really taught me the importance of having a solid design in both your front and back end and really to be clear in your api documentation.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Team-formerly-known-as/budget-book-backend">Github repo backend</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Team-formerly-known-as/budget-book-frontend">Github repo Frontend</a></p>
<p><a href="https://team-formerly-known-as.github.io/budget-book-frontend/">live site</a></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Project: Forum API</title><link>/posts/2022/forum-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:28:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/forum-api/</guid><description>This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.
This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/project-pictures/db-picture.png" alt="db-icon">This is a database for a user-generated chat forum that is ready to be paired with a front-end UI. It uses the Django-Ninja framework, Postgres, and cookie based authentication. Intended for use as a technology forum, but is suitable for multiple industries.</p>
<p>This project started off as a full stack app, intending to be my capstone project for my bootcamp. It was meant to be a technology forum for me and my cohorts to compile our resources. We had five days to complete this project.</p>
<p>Not knowing anything about Django-Ninja coming in, or anything about cookie based authentication, I spent more time studying than coding, and did not finish the front end. However, I did end up with a fully functional secure api with cookie based authentication.</p>
<p>One immediate challenge was the lack of Django-Ninja docs written on a beginner level. So there was a lot of struggle trying to fit django-ninja into what i already knew about DRF.</p>
<p>I had a lot of fun with Django-Ninjas auto-docs. They made testing very easy. My most valuable lesson from this project came in the form of setting realistic expectations when incorporating a new technology into a build. Django-Ninja did make the process much quicker once I had done enough research to fully understand it, however I underestimated the amount of time it took to get to that point which caused a delay in finishing the project.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Acer0ni/coding-forum">Github repo</a></p>
<p><a href="https://forum.pwnschool.org/api/docs">Live site</a></p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>